# SACHIN AHUJA

sachinahi@gmail.com | sachinahuja.info | Santa Monica, CA

# FULL-STACK/DATA ENGINEERING

Software engineering expert with 5 years of committed client service in business intelligence and data analytic applications. Specializes in software development and data engineering functions. Spearheads and drives a multitude of high-profile research and data analytics projects. Driven to find technical and data-centered solutions for companies' greatest challenges in an effort to add value. Serves as a leader in the mentoring and coaching of other team members by teaching techniques, processes, and applications used in data management.

#### **CORE PROFICIENCIES**

Data Engineering | Amazon Web Services | Product Management | Project Implementation | Project Management Web & Application Development | Troubleshooting | Process Improvement | End-User and Customer Support

#### **PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES**

### **ATOM TICKETS**

#### **Software Design Engineer**

2017 - Present

- Engineer a revolutionary, user-friendly, and socially-driven interface that allows movie lovers to search for films instantly, invite friends, buy tickets, pre-order concessions and enjoy a VIP experience at the theater
- Assist with the application planning, development, and deployment of Atom's and Regal's web clients using Scala, Play
   Framework, and JavaScript
- Integrate Google Pay and Chase Pay into the checkout flow assuring higher user conversion
- Reviewed and implemented special partnership promotions to help increase traffic with Amazon Prime and Lionsgate/AMEX exclusive screenings, decreasing CPA by 26%
- Implement advertisement placements with Adzerk support to manage scheduling and goal tracking
- Led the development of ADA compliance for Regal Cinemas

## **VISA**

#### Senior UI Engineer

2016 - 2017

- Charged with enhancing the UI implementation in a forward-thinking, reusable, and scalable UI architecture
- Designed React web components taken from prototypes, partnering exclusively with design, engineering, and product teams to ensure project alignment
- Developed the following web components, resulting in streamlined user experience:
   Advanced Search, Advanced Dropdown, Date-Time Picker, Status, Status Manager
- Collaborated to author documentation for the reusable web components open-sourced within the company
- Increased the coverage of the UI unit testing framework to 85% using Enzyme

#### **DRAFTCRUNCH**

#### Lead Software Developer (engineering team of two)

2015 - 2016

- Partnered with the co-founders to build venture-backed sports analytics platform for daily fantasy sports players to create, sell, and/or purchase third-party predictive models and strategies acquiring 15,000 users
- Engineered a web service, with cached architecture, master-slave cluster, and sticky sessions for web-sockets to create
  the fastest responsive lineup builder in the industry
- Developed the Lineup Builder web client using Angular.js, which serves as a complex analytical tool to analyze and create lineups

- Directed flow of assignments by delegating sub-tasks to team members and contractors, monitoring project progress along the way
- Created ETL services integrated with 3rd party APIs and web scrapers to acquire the latest information for the platform
- Crafted an image rendering microservice for social sharing of lineups to create virality
- Managed production bottlenecks, performed unit testing, and test drove development, ensuring maximum quality assurance during every phase of development

#### **TOGGA**

#### Web Developer (engineering team of three)

2014 - 2015

- Produced the first Women's World Cup fantasy app, acquiring 110,000 users, using Ionic.js and Node.js microservices deployed on Docker
- Contributed to building high-performance cloud-based REST API services, handling 30,000 daily active users using Node.js, PHP, MySQL and Redis
- Enhanced the Draft app from end to end by configuring a microservice to manage scheduled events and incorporated real-time data support using Firebase
- Spearheaded the migration of the web client architecture from jQuery to Angular.js
- Programmed an email campaign manager to augment retention by sending out weekly emails to users
- Incorporated analytics and created scripts to determine power users using Google Analytics and MixPanel

#### PROFESSIONAL PROJECTS

#### **FORTNITECLIPZ**

Designed a web app that automatically creates highlights of Twitch.tv Fortnite streams by using machine learning/artificial intelligence to recognize when key moments happen during a stream. The back-end was built using AWS serverless infrastructure, including: IAM, Route 53, CloudFormation, VPC, S3, RDS, Lambda, SQS, API Gateway, MediaConvert, CloudWatch, and Cognito. Services use FFmpeg, FFprobe, and Tesseract to manipulate and analyze video streams. The web client was built using React with Google Analytics. FortniteClipz can be found at http://www.fortniteclipz.com/

#### **EDUCATION AND TRAINING**

<b>Programming Bootcamp and Coding School</b>	MakerSquare		Austin, TX		2014
<b>Bachelor of Science in Chemical Engineering</b>	Georgia Institute of Technology	-	Atlanta, GA		2009—2013

#### **TECHNICAL PROFICIENCIES**

JAVASCRIPT	AngularJS, Handlebars.js, Ionic, jQuery, Meteor, Node.js, React, Underscore.js, Zepto.js
AMAZON WEB SERVICES	<ul> <li>API Gateway, CloudFront, CloudWatch, DynamoDB, EC2, ECS, Elastic Transcoder, IAM, Lambda, MediaConvert, RDS, Route 53, S3, Serverless, SQS</li> </ul>
DATABASE	<ul> <li>ActiveRecord, DynamoDB, MesaSQLite, MongoDB, MySQL, NoSQL, PostgreSQL, RDS, RoboMongo, SequelPro, SQLite3</li> </ul>
WEB	<ul><li>Bootstrap, Foundation, Grunt, Gulp.js, Less, Sass, SCSS, Webpack</li></ul>
OTHER	<ul> <li>DApps/Solidity, Docker, FFmpeg/FFprobe, Golang, Java, Kali Linux(Aircrack-ng), Play Framework,</li> </ul>
	Ruby on Rails, Scala, Swift, Xamarin
ANALYTICS	<ul><li>Facebook Pixel, Google Analytics, Mixpanel, Segment</li></ul>
ENGAGEMENT	<ul> <li>Adzerk, Appcues, Branch, Braze, Intercom, Tawk.to</li> </ul>
MANAGEMENT	<ul><li>Agile, Bitbucket, Confluence, GitHub, JIRA, Rally, Slack, Trello</li></ul>
NPM	<ul><li>async, cluster, cron, express, moment, mongodb, MySQL, request, rxjs, socket.io, zerorpc, zmq</li></ul>
PIP	<ul> <li>ffprobe3, matplotlib, numpy, opencv-python, pandas, pillow, pytesseract, requests, seaborn, streamlink, tensorflow</li> </ul>